http://www.ephotozine.com/terms-and-conditions/privacy-policy-3

Join for Free
Trending »
Christmas Prize Draw 2020
Nikon Z6 II
Save 69% On inPixio Software
Canon EOS 850D Rebel T8i Review
What is Plus Membership?
ADVERTISEMENT
Enter The ePHOTOzine Christmas Prize Draw!
Privacy Policy
ePHOTOzine have created the following document to explain what information we collect when you visit the ePHOTOzine web site, why we collect such information, the ways information is gathered, how we use the information and the choices you can make about these practices.
We are registered with the ICO and have taken actions to be GDPR compliant wherever applicable.
By using this Site, you consent to the data practices prescribed in this Privacy Policy. We may amend the document at any time and will indicate when we do at the bottom of the page with a "last updated" date. It is your responsibility to review this Policy frequently and remain informed about any changes to it, so we encourage you to visit this page often.
Interpretations
"you", "your", "users", and "yours" refer to the customer/purchaser/member using this site.
"ePHOTOzine", "Magezine Publishing Ltd", "we", "us", "this site" and "our" refer to Magezine Publishing Ltd.
General Viewing
When you visit ePHOTOzine, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser. These activity logs collect the following unique, but non-identifiable information: source IP address, time of access, date of access, web page(s) visited, language use, and type of browser used. We consider information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, home or other physical address, an email address, phone number or other contact information, whether at work or at home, to be "Personal Information". We do not collect "Personal Information" unless you voluntarily provide it to us. You can visit this Site without revealing any "Personal Information" about yourself.
Cookie Policy
Cookies are tiny text files that are stored on your computer when you visit many websites. Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improving the user experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.
Cookies can be "First Party", i.e. set by us, or "Third Party" ï¿½ set by another company to perform the function, for example Google Analytics or our Advertising cookies.
Our primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. Hence, this simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation by providing and saving your preferences and login information as well as providing personalized functionality. We also use cookies to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the website. We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone. Cookies do not give us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through any of the website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.
We also allow cookies to be set by a number of independent measurement, advertising and research companies. These companies read and write their own cookies onto your devices. In most cases, these cookies are used to track the adverts and keep count of the number of times that each advert is viewed by users. We use this type of information to help improve the services the website provides to you and help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers are initially set up to automatically accept cookies, but you can set your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, please be aware that should you choose to disable cookies it may prevent you from taking full advantage of our website and some of this, and other websites, may fail to work.
When you register
When you register to join in our forums, post photographs in the gallery or sign up for our newsletter it is necessary for us to collaect some personal data from you.
What data we collect and why we have it
When you sign up for an ePHOTOzine account, your personal details are submitted to our secure server which is located in a secure data centre. This is protected by HTTPS encryption. Staff members and moderators of ePHOTOzine may access this data when necessary, for example to contact you if you submit a report or to send you a prize. Below is a list of the data we collect and why we keep it.
Name –We need a name to identify you should you win a prize or should you contact us because you've forgotten your password; we may need to verify who you are by cross-checking your name with a form of ID for security purposes.
Email –We require an email address from you at sign up for verification purposes. We also use this email address to contact you where applicable. We can also send you our informative weekly editorial newsletter and any offers we think you might be interested in, if you are signed up to receive these. We take your privacy extremely seriously and will never sell your details to third parties. You can opt out of our newsletters at any time. We also send out automatic notification emails regarding your use of the site (such as to inform you of comments on your pictures; updates to your forum posts etc). Again, you can unsubscribe from these at any time.
Address –We ask for an address so that if you win a prize in either our regular site competitions or the Christmas prize draw, the prize can be sent out quickly and easily. In some instances we may not be able to confirm all address details with winners before sending prizes out, so we ask that you keep this information up to date. We will not be held responsible if you win a prize and it is sent out to the wrong address due to the information not being up to date. Supplying your address is optional. However not supplying your address may result in your competition entries being void.
Date of birth –ePHOTOzine sends out a free week’s worth of Plus Membership redeemable through a code as a birthday perk. By providing your date of birth you are authorizing us to send this to your email address. We occasionally use this data to generate anonymous demographics of the average age of users to help us tailor content and advertising better. Your birthday is also used to verify your age so that you may turn off the adult content blocker if you wish. You can choose not to give us your date of birth however this will mean that you don't get a week's free Plus Membership for your birthday. Because we can't verify your age without your birthday, you will also lose the ability to see images that are classed as adult on the site.
Where you came from – We keep a referrer URL (where you came from on the web when you sign up for an account) so that we can look at how our users reach us and optimise the site for the best user experience.
Gender –This data is used in anonymous demographic collections so we can tailor content better to our users. Providing your gender is optional.
Favourite drink/colour/gadget etc. These are completely optional as to whether you fill them out and are not used in any data collections – these answers are just for fun and to help add a bit of personality to your profile. You can edit them at any time by going to your profile settings.
Closed profile data
When you close your ePHOTOzine account, the account data remains stored on our secure servers. It is removed from public view and is not searchable or accessible from the site. We keep the account data and your photos will remain in the main gallery in case you change your mind and ask to have the profile re-opened or until you request it to be destroyed.
If you wish to have us destroy your profile and remove all data from our servers, you must request that we do so either by email or through the on-site report system and we will take the appropriate action to ensure this is carried out. Please note that once the action has been requested you will not be able to revive your profile and all your data will be permanently deleted. This is an irretrievable process. We ask that you think very carefully before making this decision as we will not be able to help with retrieving images from your profile.
When you sign up to ePHOTOzine the data remains on our server permanently, unless you ask that the data be destroyed.
When we require full Personal Information
On some ePHOTOzine Web pages you can order products, make requests and register to receive materials. The types of information collected at these pages are name, address, contact and billing information, transaction, and credit card information. This Personal Information we collect from you to help you complete a transaction and process any of your online transactions, to communicate back to you, to update you on our service and benefits, to provide you with information regarding our products and promotions, to support your use of our products and services, to personalize our Web site for you and for any other purpose related to the operation of ePHOTOzine and the programs, products and services offered on it. You always have the right to choose whether or not to provide information about yourself to Magezine Publishing Ltd. If you choose not to provide such information, you can still use this Site but you may not be able to access certain options, offers or services.
Forums and Galleries
We will, but are not obligated to, monitor areas on ePHOTOzine where users post forum messages or images. Any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should take care when disclosing personal information, such as your email address or phone number. To maintain site, content and thread continuity, we will not delete forum messages or gallery comments, unless we feel they breach our terms and conditions.
Surveys, Polls & Competitions
ePHOTOzine sometimes conducts surveys, competitions or Polls. If you answer a survey or enter a competition, you may be asked for additional information. Participation in these competitions or surveys is completely voluntary, and therefore the user has the choice of whether or not to disclose such information. Personal Information, as well as any other information, collected on this Site may be disclosed to our staff and/or agents so that they can contact you regarding our products, services, or promotional offers, respond to your requests, provide certain services to you and operate this Site and the programmes offered on it. We will not sell, lease, share or otherwise use your Personal Information except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or when stated in a specific surveys or competition details.
Making corrections and updates
We allow you to confirm, change, update, modify and delete Personal Information we hold about you. You may do this by logging into your profile and follow the necessary links to your personal data. From here you can delete or change any information you have provided to us.
Security
The ePHOTOzine site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We follow generally accepted procedures to back up data stored on our servers.
Credit cards and electronic payment
We do not store payment card details. We use third parties, PayPal and Pay 360 to process payments. All card data remains with the third parties. If you have a query regarding this, please refer to PayPal or Pay360's terms and conditions.
Children's Guidelines
ePHOTOzine encourages parents or guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the forums and galleries. However no information should be submitted by visitors under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian. Parents or guardians can request to delete their child's personal information by contacting ePHOTOzine at support@ephotozine.com.
CERTAIN EXCEPTIONAL DISCLOSURES
Magezine Publishing Ltd may disclose your Personal Information, any images in your portfolio or any images you submit to the Public Gallery if requested to do so by legal authorities, required to do so by law or believes in good faith that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to the edicts of the law or to comply with any legal process served on Magezine Publishing Ltd or this Site; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Magezine Publishing Ltd; or (3) act to protect the personal safety of users of Magezine Publishing Ltd, its websites or the public. If Magezine Publishing Ltd should ever file for bankruptcy or be acquired by a third party, merge with a third party, sell all or part of the Magezine Publishing Ltd assets, or otherwise transfer substantially all of its relevant assets to a third party, it may sell or share the Personal Information and all other information you have provided through this Site to such third party. Due to the potential for abuse of the services offered on ePHOTOzine, Magezine Publishing Ltd reserves the right to review the content of your portfolio and to provide the proper authorities with your Personal Information as well as any images or information related to child pornography or any other illegal activity found on your account.
Choice/Opt-Out
We provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from ePHOTOzine and our partners via an unsubscribe mechanism in all e-mail communication. You may "opt-out" of any marketing relationship we have with you by choosing to do so where such option is available.
In compliance with new Data protection laws we will email all members giving them the opportunity to unsubscribe quickly and easily from our newsletters. It is your responsibility to take action if you no longer wish to receive email communications from us in the future. If you do not inform us that you would like to be unsubscribed we will assume that you are still happy to receive our emails.
International Transfers
Personal Information collected on this Site may be stored and processed in the United Kingdom or any other country in which Magezine Publishing Ltd or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this Site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.
Links to Other Sites
This site contains links to other sites that may offer information, products or services that may be of interest to you. We cannot ensure the protection of any information or images that you provide to a third-party website that links to or from ePHOTOzine or any information collected by any third party, since these third-party websites are owned and operated independent of Magezine Publishing Ltd. Any information collected by these third parties is not governed by this Privacy Policy but by the privacy policy, if any, of such third party. If you have questions about a third party's information practices, please read its privacy policy. Magezine Publishing Ltd assumes no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the practices, actions or policies of such third parties, and is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such websites.
Legal Disclaimer
This Site operates "AS-IS" and "AS-AVAILABLE," without liability of any kind. We are not responsible for events beyond our direct control.
Who does ePHOTOzine share information with?
ePHOTOzine will not share personally identifiable information without your consent. We may share information about your visits with advertisers, partners, sponsors or other third parties. For example, we may disclose how frequently the average ePHOTOzine user visits the site, which products are being searched most or the average age/gender of our reader but never anything about you personally, unless you have given us permission to do so. To learn more about behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertisng.org
Business sale
If Magezine Publishing Ltd or any of its lines of business is sold, pledged or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets, bankruptcy or otherwise, then the user database of ePHOTOzine.com could be sold as part of that transaction and all User Information accessed by such successor or purchaser.
Feedback
If you have any questions, suggestions or comments about this Privacy Policy or any other documents on ePHOTOzine, you can contact us via email at support@ephotozine.com.
Magezine Publishing Ltd fully supports the protection of your privacy and works hard to protect your Personal Information. In the unlikely event that your Personal Information is disclosed inadvertently to a third party without your consent, Magezine Publishing Ltd will use its best efforts to stop the disclosure and remedy the situation upon notice. Magezine Publishing Ltd shall not be liable for any unintentional or inadvertent disclosure of any end user information.
This page was last updated on 16 May 2018 11:00AM
Reach 1.6 million Photographers; Advertise on EPZ
Follow @ephotozine
ADVERTISEMENT
ADVERTISEMENT
Things to do...
Get the latest photography news straight to your inbox by signing up to our newsletter.
Newsletter Signup
Visit our Competitions Forum, where you'll find our monthly competition and other external competitions to enter.
Photography Competitions
ADVERTISEMENT
Directory Pages
Search for all the latest photography gear and services in our dedicated photography directories.
Calibrate your monitor so you can see 16 different shades :
Username:
Password:
Remember me
Can't access your account?New to ePHOTOzine? Join Today!
×
Cookies help us deliver our service. By using our service, you agree to our use of cookies. OK Learn more
